VISITING ROOM ENTRANCE TOKYO DETENTION HOUSE
（東京拘置所會客室出入口）
It's been a long time.
好久不見了
Every month…
每個月…
you've been writing me letters.
你都會寫信給我呢
I have.
是的
Please stop.
請你別再寫了
I want…
我想寧靜地…
to die quietly.
迎接死亡
We're done here.
我們談完了
Excuse me.
不好意思
There was an error in the visiting request form
我們事務所的明墨剛才提出的
submitted by Akizumi from our office earlier.
接見申請單好像有地方填寫錯誤
He asked me to fix it up for him. Mind if I do that?
他叫我來幫他訂正，可以嗎？
Mr. Akizumi?
明墨先生是嗎？
He was here to see Mr. Yusaku Shimizu?
是找志水裕策先生的那位啊？
That's right. To see Mr. Shimizu.
是的，就是志水先生
YUSAKU SHIMIZU
我看看
Since the visit's already over, there's no need for corrections.
他已經見過對方了 不用訂正也沒關係
I see. Thank you.
這樣啊，謝謝你
Yusaku Shimizu…
志水裕策…
Is it too hot?
是不是太熱了？
Well? Do you like this?
怎麼樣？這樣舒不舒服？
There are currently 64 dogs here at the facility.
我們設施裡目前共有64隻收容犬
Do you know why these dogs were abandoned?
你覺得牠們是因為 什麼理由而被棄養的呢？
Their owners found them to be too much work,
“因為照顧起來麻煩
couldn't take them along to new homes, or their kids got bored of them.
搬家後不能養狗、小孩養膩了”
All for people's selfish reasons.
全都是因為人類的任性
In Japan, about 14,000 dogs and cats are euthanized every year.
在日本每年約有 14000隻貓狗會被安樂死
That many?
那麼多？
Just like humans, they don't get to pick their parents.
畢竟牠們跟人一樣 沒辦法選擇自己的父母
True.
說得也是
This place has actually been around for quite a while.
我們做中途之家也做了一段時間
We've been working hard for quite some time now.
從很久以前就在為牠們盡心盡力
This girl…
這女生是…
That's Saya. She's over there.
她是紗耶，本人就在那裡
Good, Mame.
小豆，你好乖喔
By the way, this Golden Retriever, Cocoa,
順帶一提，這隻黃金獵犬叫可可
is the mother of Mame over there.
是那隻小豆的媽媽
Nice, Mame.
小豆，很棒喔
Then…
那麼…
who's this woman?
這位女性是誰？
That's Ms. Momose.
那是桃瀨小姐
Where is she right now?
請問她現在人在哪裡？
She passed away a long time ago.
她在很久之前就去世了
YUSAKU SHIMIZU SENTENCED TO DEATH FOR ITOI FAMILY MURDERS
（糸井家滅門案 志水裕策被判處死刑）
Sentenced to death for murders…
因殺人罪判處死刑
The incident took place in 2012,
命案是在2012年發生的
twelve years ago from now,
距今12年前
in a residential area in Hanamigawa Ward, Chiba City, Chiba Prefecture.
在千葉縣千葉市花見川區 一處恬靜的住宅區裡
Makoto Itoi, a 42-year-old office worker,
42歲的上班族糸井誠
his 38-year-old wife Eriko,
以及38歲的妻子惠理子
and their 9-year-old daughter Natsu were murdered in their home.
還有9歲女兒奈津在自家遭到殺害
No money or valuables were taken,
由於家中財物並未失竊
leading the police to investigate it as an act of revenge.
警方便朝挾怨殺人的方向進行偵辦
And Yusaku Shimizu, Itoi's colleague, was arrested.
最後將被害人的同事 志水裕策逮捕歸案
It really wasn't me.
我真的沒有殺人
Itoi and Shimizu had been colluding to embezzle company funds.
糸井與志水長期合謀，侵占公司資金
They had a dispute over this money,
後來引發金錢糾紛
resulting in Shimizu murdering Itoi.
導致志水動手殺害糸井
Initially, Shimizu denied committing the crime,
當初志水矢口否認有犯案
but he later confessed his guilt.
但後來願意認罪
He then received a death sentence in the first trial.
日後在第一審遭判死刑
The defense counsel chose not to appeal the verdict,
辯護方未上訴
and the trial came to a close.
訴訟就此結案
This office was established only five years ago.
我們事務所是在5年前設立的
And Mr. Akizumi wasn't an attorney before that.
他在那之前並不是律師
What was he doing?
他之前在做什麼？
He was a prosecutor.
檢察官
Twelve years ago…
12年前…
Mr. Akizumi would've still been a prosecutor.
明墨律師當時還是檢察官
Why did he visit a death row inmate?
他到底是為了什麼去見死刑犯？
Isn't that him?
是不是那個人？
Masato Uno is a charismatic attorney.
明星律師，宇野雅人
Do all attorneys stay at such luxury hotels?
做律師的每個都住這麼好的飯店？
Are you jealous?
你羨慕嗎？
Curiously, he makes frequent trips to a hotel for "business reasons."
聽說不知為何 他常因為工作需要而出入飯店
USES IT FOR "BUSINESS"
（每個週末因“工作”入住）
Maybe I should've gone too.
我應該跟去才對
Don't worry. Mr. Akizumi trusts them too.
放心，明墨律師也很信賴他們
-Excuse me.
-借過一下 -不好意思
I left something in the lobby!
我有東西忘在大廳！
Seriously? Let's head back then.
搞什麼？我們快回去拿
So, that woman back there isn't involved?
剛才那位女性好像不是目標
Oh, crap.
糟糕
What are you--
你在搞什麼…
If they don't come out for over an hour, we'll know for sure.
如果超過一個小時沒出來 就確定有問題了呢
Yes.
沒錯
But I'll hit you in five seconds.
不過再過五秒，我就要揍人了
Sorry!
抱歉！
That's a pretty good angle.
你拍這張的角度不錯喔
Well done.
幹得漂亮
Thanks.
過獎了
Good work.
辛苦了
Ms. Shiraki, the rundown, please.
白木小姐，麻煩你說明案情
Right.
好的
There's been a series of rape in Chiba City, Chiba Prefecture.
發生在千葉縣千葉市的 連續不同意性交事件
The first victim is Ms. Sena Moriya.
第一名被害人是守屋瀨奈小姐
Late one night, when she returned to her home where she lived alone,
當她在深夜回到獨居住家時
a man trailing her threatened her with a knife.
遭到一名尾隨男子持小刀威脅
The man was wearing a balaclava, so she couldn't see his face.
由於該名男子穿戴露眼頭套 使被害人無法辨識出對方長相
The second victim is Ms. Kasumi Toyama.
接著是第二名被害人，遠山香澄小姐
She was targeted in the same way.
她也在同樣的手法下遇害
Both reported the incidents to the police after some time had passed.
兩名被害人都是在 遇害的一段時間後才向警方報案
Consequently, there's no evidence linking to the culprit, like DNA.
因此並未遺留下 如DNA等與犯人相關的證物
With no eyewitness accounts or physical evidence,
由於沒有任何目擊證詞 也沒有發現物證
the investigation has been difficult.
導致警方難以搜索
And on February 21st,
然後就在2月21日
the third incident occurred.
發生第三起事件
The third victim is Ms. Eri Sendo.
第三名被害人是仙道繪里小姐
She was also threatened with a knife in the same way
她也同樣遭犯人持刀威脅
and nearly pulled into her apartment.
差點被挾持進房
Please stop!
住手！
She fought back desperately, causing the man's mask to come off.
就在她拼命抵抗時，犯人的頭套脫落
Panicked, the man fled the scene.
該男子便自犯案現場倉惶逃逸
The prosecution suspected Mr. Reiji Kurusu of being the man and indicted him.
檢方判斷該男子為來栖禮二先生 並向他提起告訴
Kurusu was arrested on suspicion of sexually assaulting three women
來栖因為在千葉市內 對共計三名女性行使性暴力的罪嫌
within Chiba City.
而遭逮捕
Chiba…
千葉？
Why this case?
為什麼會挑上這個案件？
A high-profile case like this
像這種受人矚目的事件
is the perfect chance to get your name out there.
正好是打響名號的絕佳機會啊
By the way, Kurusu was found guilty
順帶一提，來栖在一年前
of committing an indecent act without consent a year ago.
因為不同意猥褻罪而被判有罪
But in this case, the only conclusive evidence
但在這一連串的事件中 唯一可說是決定性證據的
is the eyewitness account of the third incident.
就只有第三起事件的目擊證詞
Upon questioning, he confessed to the first and second incidents.
另外他在偵訊過程中
He confessed?
他坦白了？
But he hasn't admitted to the third.
就只有第三起事件他否認犯案
I assume…
這恐怕是…
this was on Attorney Uno's advice.
宇野律師教他這麼說的
So,
也就是說
you wanted to snatch this case from Attorney Uno. That's why…
是為了從宇野律師手中搶下這案子…
If you see a tasty fruit, you have to go and pluck it yourself.
必須親手摘下美味的果實
I'm happy for you.
好開心喔，對不對？
What should we have for lunch?
中午想吃什麼呢？
I want omurice!
我想吃蛋包飯！
-Omurice? -Let's see.
-蛋包飯啊？ -我看看喔
-What else? -What about this one?
-還有哪家？ -有很多間耶，還有肉呢
Here you go.
還給你
It won't fly away anymore.
這樣就不會再飛走了
Thanks!
謝謝叔叔！
-I'm so sorry. -No worries.
不好意思
So cool!
好厲害喔！
Thanks.
謝謝
What's on yours?
你拿到什麼？
Nothing.
沒什麼啦
It's been a while, Mr. Uno.
好久不見了，宇野律師
Mind if we have a little chat?
我想和你聊一下
What's this about?
這是什麼？
Do you want me to spell it out?
我可以說出來嗎？
So, you're the Akizumi.
你就是那個明墨嗎？
I don't know what this is about, but not today.
我不知道你想說什麼 但拜託不要挑今天
I understand Yua is enrolling in a private elementary school next year.
我記得夢愛明年就要讀私立小學了
How do you know that?
你為什麼會知道？
I have a very simple deal for you.
我只是想做個簡單的商量
If you accept it,
如果你答應了
you can protect both your job and your family.
就能夠同時保住工作和家庭
Seriously, you attorneys are so willful.
受不了，律師大爺就是任性
You say you'll do something, then change your mind.
一下說要辯護，一下又說不要
Everyone's got their own circumstances, after all.
每個人難免都會有不方便的時候
But still, you're lucky.
不過呢，你的運氣很好
I'll be handling your defense now,
現在起由我接任你的辯護律師
and I want to confirm something again.
有些事情得向你再次確認
You were maintaining your innocence,
你明明主張自己是冤枉的
so why did you confess?
為什麼又選擇自白呢？
Because that attorney told me to.
是那個律師叫我這麼做
"If the interrogation drags on, it'll work against us."
他說警方的偵訊越久會越不利
"You can tell the truth in court."
叫我把實話留到法庭上再講
I see.
原來是這樣啊
Just to confirm,
我再確認一次
when the third incident occurred, where were you?
第三起事件發生的當下
I went to my regular bar after work and then headed straight home to sleep.
我下班後去了常光顧的酒吧 然後就直接回家睡覺
Anything to prove that?
有辦法證明嗎？
The last time I got arrested, it was such a pain,
上次我被抓到的時候遇上不少麻煩事
so I turn off my phone when moving.
我從此移動時都會關掉手機
Say,
我問你喔
they don't have much evidence against me.
既然證據也不怎麼齊全
Is it true I'll be found innocent in the trial?
法庭是不是真的會判我無罪啊？
Of course.
當然
I promise to secure an acquittal for you.
我一定會讓你無罪獲釋
Getting a confession from him only to overturn it later.
話說回來，竟然叫他自白之後又否認
What was Attorney Uno's strategy?
宇野律師到底是想出什麼策略啊？
He is the guard, Osawa.
這位是獄警的大澤
I'm Osawa.
-敝姓大澤 -我是刑事部長倉田
This way, please.
這邊請
Are they the prefectural police?
他們是縣警嗎？
Why are they here?
為什麼會來這裡？
Has there been any change in the accused?
被告最近有什麼變化嗎？
None. He's carrying on without any issue.
沒有，他能正常生活，毫無問題
As you're probably aware,
我想你應該知道
once we arrive at the investigation room, we'll move the accused.
等你抵達偵訊室後 我們會立刻移送被告
Have a seat while you wait.
請稍坐一下等候
Mobile phones aren't permitted for use.
室內禁止使用行動電話等設備
-So I'll hold onto them. -Right.
-將由我方代為保管 -好
I still don't understand Mr. Uno's intention.
我還是搞不懂宇野律師想做什麼
Why did he make Kurusu confess to the crime?
他為什麼要叫來栖認罪呢？
If Kurusu was claiming innocence, Mr. Uno could've told him
如果要主張無罪，大可叫他否認
to deny the accusation or remain silent.
也可以一貫行使緘默權
Defending him would've been simpler that way.
那樣更容易替他辯護
It's quite a stretch to have him say, "I confessed, but it was a lie."
若他先自白，後來改口說是騙人的 就未免太牽強了
It's also odd Mr. Uno didn't make him confess to the third incident.
只有第三起事件沒有承認 這也不對勁啊
If only Kurusu had his phone turned on, he'd have had a straightforward alibi.
如果他沒有把手機關機 就可以直接拿出不在場證明了
Anyway, the eyewitness account for the third incident,
問題是最關鍵的證據
which is the conclusive evidence, conflicts with Mr. Kurusu's account.
第三起事件的目擊證詞
Wait, where's Mr. Akizumi?
奇怪，明墨律師他還沒來嗎？
Do you have an appointment?
有事先約好嗎？
Despite facing that ordeal,
你才剛遇上那種事
you're still fulfilling your duties.
居然照常回到工作崗位
Your resilience is remarkable.
看來你的內心十分堅強
I'm impressed.
我深感佩服
Who are you?
請問你是哪位？
Mr. Kurusu…
我和來栖先生啊
and I have been acquainted for some time.
是老交情
Could I speak with you later?
晚點可以耽誤你一些時間嗎？
My shift ends at 7 p.m.
我晚上七點會下班
I'm heading home.
我先走了
-Good night.
-辛苦了
I've been waiting for you.
我一直在等你
You finished work an hour early.
你提早一個小時下班啊
I've told the police everything.
我已經全都向警察說過了
Ask them for details.
如果想知道什麼事，請去問他們
My apologies.
非常抱歉
You see, a few aspects of your testimony trouble me.
你的證詞中有一點讓我有些在意
-Who are you? -May I ask a few questions?
-你到底是誰？ -方便請教一下嗎？
Keep it brief.
請長話短說
On the day of the incident,
事件發生當日
you were threatened with a knife.
你遭人持小刀威脅
You fought back desperately,
在頑強抵抗之後
and saw the man's face.
看見了那名男子的長相
The man panicked and fled the scene.
於是男子便慌忙逃離現場
I hear that is your testimony.
你的證詞是這麼說的
Is this correct?
沒錯吧？
What about it?
那又怎樣？
Were you acquainted with Mr. Kurusu?
你和來栖先生認識嗎？
Ask him yourself.
你去問他本人啊
It's a minor detail,
另外還有一個非常小的細節
but there's a convenience store just 13 steps from the crime scene.
在離案發現場13步遠的地方 有一間便利商店
When you were threatened with a knife
當你在公寓前被人持刀威脅時
I was overwhelmed with panic and couldn't think clearly.
因為我當時腦中一片混亂 單純沒有想到要那麼做
If you had shouted, surely someone would have noticed.
如果你有大聲呼救 照理來說也會有人發現
But no one has come forward with such testimony yet.
但目前還沒有收集到類似的證詞
Two days later, you went to the police
兩天後你才去了警局
to submit a victim's report.
並填寫報案單
Why didn't you report the crime to the police right after it happened?
為什麼你沒有在遇害後馬上報案呢？
Because--
那是因為…
It's difficult to speak out against sex crimes.
性犯罪的被害者很難出面發聲
You wouldn't understand.
你不可能明白的
Can I go now?
我可以走了嗎？
It appears Uno really did resign from Kurusu's defense.
宇野看來正式放棄為來栖辯護了
Akizumi…
“明墨”
Were you aware?
你認識他嗎？
It's fine.
不用擔心
Kurusu has already confessed to the crime.
來栖他已經承認犯案了
Nothing will change now.
事到如今不會再有任何改變
Anyway, about the incident in Funabashi--
比起這個，船橋那起案子…
Why make him confess?
叫他自白到底有什麼目的？
SERIES OF RAPE IN CHIBA
（千葉連續不同意性交案）
ITOI FAMILY MURDERS CHIBA PREFECTURE
（糸井家滅門案 千葉縣）
The Itoi family murders happened in Chiba as well.
糸井家滅門案也是在千葉發生的啊
Up until now,
目前經手過的事件
Mr. Akizumi has never chosen cases solely for the client's defense.
明墨律師不是單純為了辯護而選的
In many cases, including those involving Mr. Hiyama and Shoichiro,
他不論是面對緋山先生還是正一郎
With this case,
而且這次的案件
he went as far as threatening another attorney to secure it.
還是不惜恐嚇其他律師也要搶到手的
Is he planning something again?
難道他又在計畫什麼嗎？
Still working?
還在加班嗎？
I've been looking into what I can do until Mr. Matsunaga's retrial.
在松永先生的事件再審之前 我想看看能再做些什麼
I see. Good luck.
這樣啊，你要加油喔
Thanks.
好的
My own path, huh?
要走我自己的路，是嗎？
It seems…
赤峰先生…
Mr. Akamine is beginning to catch on.
他似乎察覺到了
But it's not time yet, right?
但還不是時候，沒錯吧？
No.
對
This case might be the crisis.
這次的事件或許會是最大的難關呢
Right.
是啊
So keep pretending
所以就麻煩你保持現狀
like you're oblivious to everything.
裝作什麼都不知道
Understood.
我明白了
Mr. Matsunaga.
松永先生
Just a little longer.
請你再忍忍
Please wait a little longer.
再給我一點時間
I will…
我…
prove…
我會證明…
your innocence.
你的清白
That day, he was drinking until 1 a.m. as usual.
我記得那天他就像往常一樣 在這裡喝到凌晨一點左右
How do you feel about Mr. Kurusu's arrest?
關於來栖先生被逮捕這件事 店長，你有什麼看法？
The way he looked at women was creepy.
他看女生時的眼光
It looked like he only saw them as objects of desire.
像是只把對方當成發洩性慾的對象 讓人感到很不舒服
"All women fall in love with me."
“全天下的女人都會愛上我”
He was completely misguided.
他還這麼誤解呢
Disgusting.
有夠噁心的
He could actually be quite kind.
別看他那副德性 其實他有時候還挺貼心的
When taking out the trash,
像是倒垃圾的時候
he'd help out the elderly woman downstairs by taking out hers too.
他還會順便幫樓下的老奶奶拿
Good day.
你好啊
Thank you.
謝謝你
People have different sides to them depending on the situation.
每個人在不同場合 都會表現出不同的面相呢
It's not about one being the real Mr. Kurusu.
與其問哪個才是真正的來栖先生
Both versions are probably the real him.
不如說每個都是真實的他
-Excuse me. -Yes?
-不好意思 -是
-A noodle refill, firm, please. -Sure thing.
-我要續麵，要硬一點的 -好的
Um…
那個…
Can I share a hypothetical scenario?
我可以說一件假設的事嗎？
What if… I mean, it's a big what if…
我只是假設，是假設喔
Mr. Akizumi has a motive again for taking on this case?
明墨律師他接下這起事件 背後會不會又有其他目的？
I mean, it's odd for him to actively pursue a case in Chiba.
你想想，這怎麼看都不對勁 還特地挑千葉的事件
Especially considering the client didn't approach him.
而且還不是別人委託我們
He took the case by force.
是搶過來的
Here you are.
久等了
It's like his past cases.
之前的案子也是一樣
Hiyama had committed a crime.
緋山他確實犯了罪
But in exchange for securing Hiyama's acquittal,
但律師他卻以換取緋山無罪為代價
he exposed the prosecution's corruption.
揭露了檢方背後的黑暗面
In the following case, he didn't secure another acquittal as expected.
在下一個事件中 還以為他又要讓正一郎無罪
But instead, he exposed the corruption of politicians.
卻在過程中讓政治家的黑暗面曝光
In both instances, he exposed the people behind the incidents,
每一次都針對事件背後的人
condemning those who sought to gain an advantage through unlawful means.
撻伐那些使用不法手段 企圖謀取利益的人
Maybe he has another motive.
這次可能也有什麼目的
For instance, if Kurusu confesses to his crime,
來栖如果認了罪，會有誰得到好處？
it would benefit the police, who have struggled to arrest the culprit until now.
那就是一直以來都抓不到犯人的警方
I think Mr. Akizumi is selecting these cases deliberately.
明墨律師他一定是刻意挑選這種事件
If the police…
如果警方…
DAD
（父親）
Huh?
怎麼了？
Don't you have to get that?
你不接嗎？
It's fine.
沒關係
I got a message.
我收到訊息了
The next public trial will take place in the same courthouse.
下次公審將於此法庭進行
All rise.
請起立
Ayuka, I never thought you were on Mr. Datehara's team.
真是沒想到 步佳居然會跟著伊達原先生做事
It must be tough working under him.
在他底下工作很辛苦吧？
Not at all. I learn a great deal from him.
不會，我學到很多
Really?
是嗎？
That's what a good subordinate says.
好下屬都一定會說那種話
I'm just being honest.
我只是陳述事實而已
Ms. Seko, you and Mr. Datehara have quite a history, right?
瀨古小姐和伊達原先生是舊識？
We're just stuck together.
算是孽緣吧
Prosecutors and judges have an inextricable link, after all.
畢竟檢察官和判事 是再怎麼切割也密不可分的
True.
說得也是
Anyway, he's risen to the position of Chief Prosecutor.
不過我很意外，他居然升上了檢事正
Quite impressive.
真是了不起呢
I've heard rumors about you becoming a Supreme Court Justice soon.
我聽說瀨古小姐 也快要當上最高法院判事了
Oh, please. Who told you that?
討厭，是誰亂說的？
Bye.
先失陪囉
Good day.
再見
He snatched the case?
他搶走了？
Yes, the serial rape case in Chiba.
是的，就是千葉那起 連續不同意性交事件
Is Mr. Akizumi planning another dramatic move?
明墨律師又打算有高調的舉動了？
I see.
這下我懂了
Hey, you.
我說啊
Yes?
怎麼了？
Could I…
可以拜託你一件事嗎？
Excuse me.
不好意思
Hey.
是你啊
You recalled something about Ms. Eri?
聽說你想起繪里小姐的事了？
Actually, that gentleman over there…
其實是那位客人…
How about you join me for a drink for once?
你們兩個偶爾來喝一杯如何？
Hello.
你們好啊
So, in a nutshell…
簡單來說，她那個人啊
she's a romantic.
就是有戀愛體質
A romantic?
戀愛體質？
-Cheers. -Thanks.
-乾杯 -謝謝
She can't sit still unless she's in love.
她只要一時半刻 沒有愛上別人就不會滿意
Anyway, she falls for people quickly and even says she spends money on them.
總之就是見一個愛一個 好像還會花錢養男人
I see.
原來是這樣啊
Based on your appearance, you're a detective, right?
你們是偵探對不對？
You're looking into Ms. Eri's twisted habit.
是不是在調查繪里小姐的糟糕嗜好？
-Habit? -Her stalking habit.
-嗜好？ -她是跟蹤狂
Any clue who she's fixated on?
你知道是哪位被跟蹤嗎？
She brought me here saying there was a guy she's interested in.
有一天她帶我過來 說她在這裡看上了一個男人
Then he started flirting with me.
結果那個男的來找我搭訕
That made her really upset.
她看到那一幕超火大的
Um, do you have a picture?
請問一下，有照片嗎？
You want to see it?
想看嗎？
I can show you if you go on a date with me.
如果你肯跟我出去約會，我就給你看
Huh? Does that mean she gave false testimony?
什麼？意思是她做了偽證？
That's right.
沒錯
The incident involving Ms. Eri Sendo, the third victim, was fabricated.
第三名被害人 仙道繪里小姐的事件是被捏造出來的
But that's too…
太離譜了吧
In this case,
在這次一連串的事件中
there were two consecutive instances of harm.
接連傳出兩次被害
However, it took time to catch the perpetrator,
但是犯人還逍遙法外
and media coverage intensified.
媒體更是大肆報導
The Chiba Police, facing ongoing criticism,
飽受批判的千葉縣警
must have been feeling quite nervous.
應該急得跳腳吧
And then, the third incident occurred.
這時候又發生了第三次
Ms. Eri Sendo provided an eyewitness testimony as the victim,
有了被害人仙道繪里小姐的證詞
prompting the police to finally arrest Mr. Kurusu.
警察終於奮起，逮捕了來栖先生
There's a big difference between the first two incidents and the third.
但第一起、第二起事件 和第三起事件之間卻有個很大的差異
What is it?
知道是什麼嗎？
Mr. Kurusu confessed to the first two but not the third.
前兩個事件都有得到來栖先生的自白 但是第三起並沒有
Right. Anything else?
沒錯，還有嗎？
In the third incident, the victim was stalking Mr. Kurusu.
第三起事件的被害人 當時正在跟蹤來栖先生
She was following him everywhere, it was really terrible.
她一直纏著這個人不放 害我也好頭痛喔
How did Ms. Eri get acquainted with Mr. Kurusu in the first place?
重點是繪里小姐 是怎麼認識來栖先生的？
I think this is how.
應該是透過這個吧
He sure is handsome, isn't he?
他看起來是很帥沒錯
Ms. Eri saw photos of Mr. Kurusu and fell for him instantly.
繪里小姐看到來栖先生的照片 因而對他一見鍾情
Then, according to her colleague, she began frequenting this bar.
從此經常光顧那間店 她的同事也是這麼說的
She pursued him relentlessly, even ambushing him every day.
還說她百般糾纏 幾乎每天都在店裡埋伏
Due to Mr. Kurusu's prior criminal record for a sexual offense
千葉縣警認為 來栖先生有性犯罪的前科
and resemblance to the suspect's description,
而且又與犯人形象一致
the Chiba Police suspected him and began surveilling him.
在追查時就已經預設他可能是犯人
So, it wasn't hard for the police officer investigating the case
在此情況下 於那家酒吧調查事件的員警
to encounter Ms. Eri at the bar, who was stalking Mr. Kurusu.
要和正在跟蹤他的繪里小姐相遇 並不是什麼難事
Then, Ms. Eri discovered that Mr. Kurusu was a rape suspect.
這時繪里小姐得知
It must have been a shock for her…
內心想必大受打擊吧
to learn that the man she loved had a liking for other women besides herself.
發現她喜歡的男人
Ms. Eri was infatuated with him enough to stalk him.
繪里小姐迷戀一個男人 甚至愛到變成跟蹤狂
It's not surprising if she felt betrayed and wanted to make him experience hell.
覺得自己遭到背叛後
So, did Ms. Eri invent the story and report it to the police?
所以繪里小姐她就編造故事 然後謊報給警察？
Who knows whether it was the police or Ms. Eri who came up with the idea?
我們不知道是警方先找上她 還是繪里小姐先謊報
It's just one possibility.
這不過是一種可能性
As for the police,
但對警察來說
they could arrest Mr. Kurusu, whom they were convinced was the culprit.
這樣就能逮捕他們已經 一口咬定是犯人的來栖先生
Once arrested,
只要逮到了人
they could question him extensively about the previous two incidents.
就可以針對前兩起事件盡情做偵訊
And if they could get a confession, it wouldn't be a mistaken arrest.
只要中途得到自供就不算是誤認逮捕
As for Ms. Eri, she could punish the man who had hurt her.
對繪里小姐來說 這樣也能處罰傷害到她的男人
It's not a bad deal for either party.
站在雙方角度，這都是不錯的條件
Here's Attorney Uno's defense record thus far.
這是宇野律師過去的辯護紀錄
He's famous for highlighting
宇野律師一向擅長博取酌量減刑
In other words,
但反過來說
he has secured a guilty verdict in every case he's handled.
就表示他負責過的案件 每一次都是以有罪收場
What if there was a deal with the police behind this?
若他和警察之間 私下有不正當地交易呢？
I've been hearing bad rumors about Attorney Uno for some time.
我從很久以前就有耳聞過 宇野律師的負面傳聞了
Upon investigation, I confirmed his frequent contact
經過我調查
That's the detective who arrested Mr. Kurusu.
他不就是逮捕了來栖先生的刑警嗎？
The police and Attorney Uno were colluding in secret
難道警察和宇野律師早就暗中勾結
to convict Mr. Kurusu?
打算判來栖先生有罪？
So, if we expose this Detective Onishi…
那只要能攻陷這個叫大西的刑警…
No, this is where it gets tricky.
不，接下來才是大問題
-Mr. Aoyama. -Right.
-青山先生 -好的
That's Ms. Eri's apartment.
這是繪里小姐住的公寓？
He is Isao Kurata.
倉田功
It is significant
縣警刑事部長本人 竟出現在被害人面前
Was he aware of Ms. Eri's false testimony?
難道刑事部長也知道 繪里小姐在做偽證嗎？
He likely visited her to strategize
他可能是接到了辯護律師換人的報告
after hearing about the change in defense attorneys.
為了擬訂法庭上的對策而造訪的
But this picture alone won't prove anything.
可是只有這張照片不能證明什麼
Chief Kurata entered Ms. Eri's apartment.
倉田刑事部長走進了 繪里小姐住的公寓
That is the crucial point.
那項事實才是最重要的
Now…
接下來…
who should we bring down first?
要先擊潰哪一邊呢？
Thank you so much for coming all this way.
有勞你跑一趟，真不好意思啊
Please don't be so guarded.
請你別抱這麼重的戒心嘛
Now and in the past, the police and prosecution
不管是從前還是現在，警察和檢察官
have always been friends.
不都是好夥伴嗎？
Please relax and take a seat.
請你隨意坐吧
Why did you want to see me today?
今天找我來是有什麼事？
Is your daughter doing well?
你女兒過得還好嗎？
My daughter is 12 now, in her first year of junior high.
我女兒現在也滿12歲，上國一了
Take a look at this.
給你看一下
See?
你瞧瞧
Isn't she cute?
是不是很可愛呀？
The thing is…
其實…
Lately, it seems this attorney called Akizumi or something
這一陣子
is causing quite a stir.
好像到處在惹事呢
And…
據說他和你們要處理的事件有關
Are you aware of this?
你知情嗎？
Yes.
我知道
I'm relieved to hear that.
那就再好不過了
Well, I knew that you, as the Chief of Criminal Investigations,
我就知道，刑事部長你這個人
wouldn't let your guard down.
是絕對不會鬆懈的
We will never cause any trouble for you, Chief Prosecutor.
我們是絕對不會給檢事正 添上任何麻煩的
Oh, please.
別這麼說啦
Don't misunderstand. I'm not concerned at all.
請你不要誤會，我一點也不擔心
In fact…
不如說呢
I trust you.
我還很信任你
If you make a face like that, your daughter will dislike you.
你擺出那種表情，當心被女兒討厭喔
Don't you agree?
是不是？
It's Chief Kurata, isn't it?
應該會從倉田刑事部長先下手吧？
That's who Mr. Akizumi wants to bring down.
剛才明墨律師有說要先擊潰哪一邊
I don't think he's targeting Ms. Eri or Attorney Uno.
我想他的目標不是繪里小姐 也不是宇野律師
I think he was after Chief Kurata from the start.
而是打從一開始 就鎖定倉田刑事部長了
Ms. Shinomiya…
紫之宮小姐
I…
我…
I believe…
我覺得啊
that if someone has committed a crime, even if they're our client,
即使是我們的委託人，如果犯了罪
they should repent and serve time.
就應該好好反省，服完刑期才對
That's why…
所以…
I still can't accept Hiyama's case.
我直到現在還是沒辦法 接受緋山那次的結果
But that's also why I believe Mr. Akizumi has acted with a motive
但也因為這樣
as well as in this current case.
都是抱持著某種意圖在行動
I--
我…
Yusaku Shimizu.
志水裕策
That's the name of the culprit in the Itoi family murders 12 years ago
這是12年前發生在千葉縣 千葉市花見川區的
in Hanamigawa Ward, Chiba City, Chiba Prefecture.
糸井家滅門案的犯人的名字
Twelve years ago?
12年前？
Mr. Akizumi went to see this man.
明墨律師他曾經去見過這個男人
YUSAKU SHIMIZU SENTENCED TO DEATH FOR ITOI FAMILY MURDERS
（糸井家滅門案 志水裕策被判處死刑）
This case was also within the Chiba Police's jurisdiction.
這案件也是歸千葉縣警管轄的
It occurred when Mr. Akizumi was still a prosecutor,
這是他轉職為律師前
before becoming an attorney.
還是檢察官時的事件
-Um-- -Could it be a complete coincidence?
-那個… -這會是一場巧合嗎？
CHIBA PREFECTURAL POLICE HEADQUARTERS
（千葉縣警察總部）
Excuse me!
不好意思！
Yes?
什麼事？
I'm sorry. I mistook you for someone else.
抱歉，我認錯人了
Is something the matter?
有什麼事嗎？
May I have a moment?
能問你幾句話嗎？
Right.
好的
What is it?
怎麼了？
It looks like Attorney Akizumi's staff is watching outside.
明墨律師的部下好像在外面埋伏
I see.
這樣啊
It's safer to leave from the back, just in case.
保險起見，我建議你走後門出去
Right.
我知道了
I have something to discuss with you.
我有事情想和你說
Well, I don't.
但我沒有
Reiji Kurusu.
來栖禮二
It's about the man who was indicted on suspicion of rape.
我想問和這名因不同意性交罪 而遭起訴的男子有關的事
You're aware of this case, right?
你應該知道這起案件吧？
You're in the way. Move aside.
你擋到我了，讓開
Please wait.
請你等一下
Wait!
別走！
Right.
是
I understand.
明白了
Excuse me.
那我掛了
I had no idea
萬萬沒想到
that Chief Kurata is your…
倉田刑事部長原來是你的…
Do the others know about this?
其他人知道這件事嗎？
I think Mr. Akizumi…
明墨律師的目標…
was targeting my father from the start.
應該從一開始就是家父
If you're willing…
如果不介意的話
could you tell me
也可以告訴我嗎？
about you and your father?
我想知道紫之宮小姐與你父親的事
My father…
父親他啊
was also my role model.
曾經是我嚮往的目標
He was kind,
他很溫柔
family-oriented,
處處為家人著想
and had a strong sense of justice.
正義感又強
I wanted to be just like him.
我想成為像他一樣的人
But my father stopped smiling.
但是他變得再也不笑了
After a certain point 12 years ago.
自從12年前的某個時候開始
Twelve years ago?
12年前？
Do you mean…
該不會…
It was around the same time as the Itoi family murders.
和糸井家滅門案是同個時期
Back then, my father…
我父親當時…
was in the First Investigation Division of the Chiba Police.
任職於千葉縣警搜查一課
I'm really busy right now.
現在是我正忙的時候啊
He began devoting himself even more to work.
他變得比往常還要更專注在工作上
And he started fighting constantly with my mother.
也變得時常和母親吵架
Are you stupid?
你是蠢蛋嗎？
A few years later, they divorced.
幾年後他們就離婚了
You think this is okay?
你真的認為這樣做就好？
Why did my father suddenly change?
為什麼父親會忽然變了個人？
Back then, I had no way of knowing.
我當時也無從得知原因
Still…
即使是這樣
I respected my father.
我還是很尊敬他
So, I talked to him a lot about me becoming an attorney.
我也和他討論過許多次 想成為律師的事
But…
可是…
six years ago…
就在6年前
On the day I graduated university…
我大學畢業那一天…
A man was visiting my father.
有個男人拜訪了父親
I couldn't tell clearly what they were discussing.
我當時沒聽清楚他們在說些什麼
But…
我只看到…
I remember the man's face.
那個人的長相
It was Mr. Akizumi?
是明墨律師？
Go away.
拜託你回去
Answer me, Mr. Kurata.
請告訴我，倉田先生
You unlawfully covered that up, didn't you?
你是不是用不正當手段 掩蓋了那件事？
Covered up.
“掩蓋”
Those words…
只有那兩個字…
they're etched in my memory.
深深留在我的記憶中
My father didn't say anything back.
父親當時什麼也沒有回答
I don't know what happened after that
至於之後的事情
because I wasn't living with my father.
我和他並沒有住在一起 自然也不知道
But…
然而…
after I passed the bar examination,
就在我司法考試合格後
I suddenly received an official job offer from the Akizumi Law Office.
明墨法律事務所 突然主動說想正式僱用我
When I saw Mr. Akizumi…
我一看到明墨律師就認出來了
I instantly recognized him as the same man.
他就是那時候的男人
So, you joined this office?
所以你才會進這間事務所？
I figured if I stayed with Mr. Akizumi…
我想說只要待在明墨律師身邊
I might learn more about my father.
或許就有機會了解父親的事
Have you questioned Mr. Akizumi about this?
你有問過明墨律師嗎？
But when you mentioned that Mr. Akizumi
但我一聽見你說他會去見 糸井家滅門案的犯人
had been meeting Yusaku Shimizu, the culprit of the Itoi family murders…
志水裕策的時候
everything fell into place.
一切就說得通了
So, 12 years ago,
也就是說12年前
Chief Kurata was handling this case…
倉田刑事部長負責偵辦那起事件…
And he might have unlawfully covered something up.
他可能在過程中 用不正當手段隱瞞了某件事情
Just as I suspected…
果然如此
Mr. Akizumi is using Ms. Eri's case to bring down Chief Kurata.
明墨律師打算利用繪里小姐的事件 打擊倉田刑事部長
Perhaps to reveal the injustice in Yusaku Shimizu's case?
而這都是為了揭露 志水裕策事件中的弊端？
Mr. Shimizu…
志水先生是…
was falsely accused.
被冤枉的
I want…
我想寧靜地…
to die quietly.
迎接死亡
We're done here.
我們談完了
Mr. Shimizu!
志水先生！
I promise…
我保證…
to secure an acquittal for you.
一定會讓你獲判無罪
Right from the start,
明墨律師他從一開始
Mr. Akizumi knew I was Kurata's daughter.
就知道我是倉田的女兒
That's why he invited me here.
所以我才會被叫來這裡
Impossible.
不會吧
Being my father's daughter…
身為女兒的我
makes me a vulnerability for him.
會成為父親的一大弱點
To expose Kurata's unlawful dealings,
為了成功揭露倉田不正執法的事實
Mr. Akizumi is trying to use me.
明墨律師打算利用我
Excuse me.
打擾了
Welcome!
歡迎啊…
It's from my father.
是我父親傳來的
He wants to meet and talk to me.
他說想和我面對面談談
I hear you've been doing pretty well.
你似乎滿活躍的嘛
Not as much as you, Mr. Datehara.
還遠遠比不上你呢
Subtitle translation by: Ai Matsuoka
字幕翻譯：江俊諺
What did you cover up?
你到底掩蓋了什麼事？
One lie connected three parties that shouldn't have been linked.
原本不可能搭上線的三人 因一個謊言而串聯在一起
Are you saying we need to break their ties?
只要打破關係就行？
The hero of justice who clears a false accusation…
你自認是替人平反冤案的正義英雄…
Is that your aim?
是不是？
From now on, it's in your hands, Akamine.
接下來的成功與否會取決於你，赤峰
I'll reveal this fact in court.
我要在法庭上揭露這項事實
Shall we get started soon?
差不多該開始了吧
Dad!
爸爸！